And welcome now to the code for our user interface, which we will find in this Python module.
そして､ このPythonモジュールにあるユーザーインターフェースのコードへようこそ｡
Price is right dot pi.
価格は適正なドットパイ｡
And this is where we will be looking at particularly the code that constructs the UI behind our product.
そしてここでは､ 特に製品の背後にあるUIを構築するコードを見ていく｡
And it starts with a few imports.
そして､ それはいくつかの輸入品から始まる｡
This very important one to import Gradio.
グラディオを輸入する上で非常に重要なものだ｡
And this even more important one to import the deal agent framework, which is at the heart of what
さらに重要なのは､ ディール・エージェントの枠組みを輸入することだ｡
Uh, and then it defines a class app.
そして､ クラス・アプリを定義する｡
And if I scroll to the bottom, you'll see that at the bottom it calls app dot run.
一番下までスクロールすると､ 一番下にapp dot runとあるのがわかるだろう｡
It creates app and then runs it.
アプリを作成し､ それを実行する｡
And what does that involve creating?
そして､ それは何を創造することなのか？
It does very little.
ほとんど何もしない｡
It just sets an empty variable for agent framework.
エージェントフレームワークのために空の変数を設定するだけだ｡
The juice the meat is in the run uh method.
肉汁は "ラン・アー "方式だ｡
And that of course creates a user interface using Gradio more advanced construct of great blocks with
そしてそれはもちろん､ 「プライス・イズ・ライト」の素晴らしいブロックを使ったGradioのより高度な構造を使ったユーザーインターフェイスを生み出す｡
Um, and then what you see here is some code that's quite similar to the code that we've already looked
それから､ ここにあるのは､ 前に見たコードとよく似たコードだ｡
In fact, the user interface part of it right here is identical.
実際､ ここにあるユーザーインターフェースの部分は同じだ｡
We have some rows with some titles.
いくつかのタイトルの行がある｡
Um, and then we include our data frame.
それからデータフレームを入れる｡
It has description price estimate discount and Earl as the columns.
これは､ 列として説明価格見積もり割引とアールを持っています｡
And it's set up and assigned to something called opportunities data frame just as before.
そして､ 以前と同じように機会データフレームと呼ばれるものにセットアップされ､ 割り当てられる｡
Uh, the only thing that's changed is what's coming right afterwards.
ええと､ 唯一変わったのは､ その直後に起こることだ｡
So here we go.
それでは､ どうぞ｡
This is the new stuff in this file.
これがこのファイルの新しい内容だ｡
There is, uh, a UI dot load.
UIのドットロードがあるんだ｡
So this is again where we tell Gradio.
だから､ ここでもグラディオに言うのだ｡
When you load, we want you to carry out a particular, uh, instruction.
ロードするときは､ ある指示を実行してほしい｡
And we specify that using the standard format for gradio, where you start with the name of the function,
そして､ gradioの標準フォーマットである関数名から始まるフォーマットを使って､
it should call the inputs and the outputs.
入力と出力を呼び出すように指定する｡
And in this case we're saying we want you to call the function called start.
そしてこの場合､ startという関数を呼び出してほしいと言っているのだ｡
There are no inputs to this function.
この機能には入力はない｡
And whatever it returns, we want you to hook that up to the opportunities data frame.
そして､ それが何を返すにせよ､ それを機会データフレームにフックしてほしい｡
And that means we expect it to return some information that is suitable to be put into a table.
つまり､ テーブルに入れるのに適した情報を返してくれることを期待しているのだ｡
So that's what we expect to see from a function start.
だから､ 機能的なスタートが期待できる｡
And then we're going to create another Gradio UI component called a GR dot timer.
そして､ GRドットタイマーと呼ばれるGradio UIコンポーネントを作成します｡
And that is something which which does some timing.
そして､ それはいくつかのタイミングを計るものだ｡
It is in fact a UI component which is invisible.
これは実際には目に見えないUIコンポーネントである｡
It's something that runs behind the scenes and it will wake up every 60s.
それは舞台裏で動いているもので､ 60年代には必ず目を覚ます｡
And what does it do every 60s well, you have to tell Gradio what it should do.
そして､ 60秒ごとに何をするかというと......グラディオに何をすべきかを指示しなければならない｡
And the way you tell Gradio is by calling timer, dot, tick.
Gradioに伝える方法は､ タイマー､ ドット､ ティックを呼び出すことだ｡
And when you do that, you provide the information to Gradio again using the standard Gradio structure
そして､ そうしたら､ Gradioの標準的な構造標準的なアプローチを使って､ 再びGradioに情報を提供する｡
You tell it the function that will be called.
呼び出される関数を指定する｡
In this case I say go.
この場合､ 私は行けと言う｡
You give it the inputs, there aren't any and the outputs, whatever go returns should be put into the
入力を与えれば､ 何もない｡ 出力は､ 何が返ってきても､ 機会データフレームに入れなければならない｡
Again, simple as that.
もう一度言う｡
The select method here that's that we call is exactly the same as before.
ここで呼び出すセレクト・メソッドは､ 以前とまったく同じだ｡
It's another thing that hasn't changed.
これも変わらないことだ｡
It's not exactly the same.
全く同じではない｡
It's changed a tiny bit, but it's basically the same.
少し変わったけど､ 基本的には同じだよ｡
And it ends with a call to the agent framework planner messenger alert, alert about the opportunity.
そして､ エージェントフレームワークのメッセンジャーアラート､ チャンスについてのアラートへのコールで終わる｡
So you probably noticed the small the small change there.
だから､ その小さな変化にお気づきだろう｡
It's going to do a full alert.
完全な警戒態勢に入る｡
Uh, and all that remains is for us to go and look at the two functions we're expecting to see start
さて､ あとは2つの機能を見ていくだけだ｡
And at the top of the display you will find is indeed start and go the two functions in question.
そしてディスプレイの上部には､ 問題の2つの機能であるスタートとゴーが表示される｡
And if we look at them, let's start with start.
そして､ それらを見るなら､ まずはスタートから始めよう｡
What start does is it creates a new instance of the deal agent framework.
スタートが行うのは､ ディール・エージェント・フレームワークの新しいインスタンスを作成することだ｡
The key object that controls our whole framework.
フレームワーク全体をコントロールする重要なオブジェクト｡
It instantiates it, and it then asks it for its memory of what opportunities does it have.
それをインスタンス化し､ どのような機会があるかを記憶させる｡
And then it calls this function table for with these opportunities and it returns that table.
そして､ これらの機会を表す関数テーブルを呼び出し､ そのテーブルを返す｡
So what does table four do.
では､ テーブル4は何をしているのか｡
Table four is this tiny function up here.
テーブル4はこの小さな機能だ｡
So table four takes opportunities.
だから､ 4番テーブルはチャンスがある｡
And then you remember opportunities if we go in here.
そして､ ここに入ればチャンスを思い出すことができる｡
Opportunities are these objects here.
チャンスはここにある｡
That is exactly what gets stored in the memory of the agent framework contains a deal an estimate and
それこそが､ エージェントフレームワークのメモリに保存される､ 取引と見積もりと値引きを含むものである｡
That is an opportunity.
それはチャンスだ｡
So we go back to week eight.
そこで第8週に戻る｡
So um, the this function converts an opportunity object into just a list of strings.
つまり､ この関数は機会オブジェクトを単なる文字列のリストに変換する｡
A list of lists of strings with the description, the price, the estimate, the discount, the URL
説明､ 価格､ 見積もり､ 割引､ URL､ 正確にはタイプ､ ここにあるデータ・フレームに入れるために必要な構造を持つ文字列のリストのリスト｡
So again, start just simply creates a deal.
だからまた､ 単純に取引を開始する｡
Agent framework.
エージェントのフレームワーク｡
Looks at its memory, converts that into strings and returns it and go.
メモリを見て､ それを文字列に変換して返す｡
Which is the thing that gets called every 60s.
60年代には必ず呼ばれたものだ｡
Go is going to do something very, very similar.
囲碁は非常に､ 非常に似たことをやろうとしている｡
You'll see it looks very similar.
よく似ているのがわかるだろう｡
It just has this one little tiny line added, a tiny little line.
ただ､ この小さな小さな一本の線が追加されているだけだ｡
It doesn't do very much.
大したことはできない｡
It does everything.
何でもやってくれる｡
This is the line that calls run on our agent framework.
これは､ エージェントフレームワーク上で実行される呼び出しの行である｡
It's the thing that we were doing manually before.
以前は手作業でやっていたことだ｡
It triggers the entire workflow that we have built.
私たちが構築したワークフロー全体がトリガーされる｡
And that's what go does.
それが囲碁だ｡
And go will be kicked off every 60s by this GR timer so that that is the business of it.
そして､ このGRタイマーによって､ 60歳ごとに碁はキックオフされる｡
All that remains is to see it working in action.
あとは実際に動いているところを見るだけだ｡
And so now to see this happening, we're going to go to the launcher and we're going to open a new terminal.
ランチャーで新しいターミナルを開いてみよう｡
And I'm going to change to my to activate my conda environment with conda activate LMS.
そして､ conda activate LMSでconda環境を有効化するように変更します｡
There we go.
これでよし｡
And now I can run it by just typing Python price is right.
今はPython price is rightと入力するだけで実行できる｡
Dot py should be as simple as that.
ドットパイはそれくらいシンプルであるべきだ｡
Let's see a bit of a drum roll.
ちょっとドラムロールを見てみよう｡
And 321.
そして321だ｡
Here we go.
さあ､ 始めよう｡
There's a pause while it thinks for a second and bam!
ちょっと考えている間に間があって､ バーン！
Up comes the price is right and there's more work going on.
値段も手頃だし､ もっと仕事がある｡
And here we see right in front of us.
そして､ 目の前にあるのがこれだ｡
What we're looking at, of course, is the memory.
もちろん､ 私たちが見ているのは記憶だ｡
We're looking at the opportunities that it's come up with.
我々はそれがもたらすチャンスに注目している｡
And we can scroll down and see this bottom item here.
下にスクロールして､ 一番下の項目を見てみよう｡
I do believe that that is the item that was just surfaced to us most recently, when we ran it from
それは､ 以前コマンドラインから実行したときに､ つい最近私たちに表面化した項目だと思う｡
Um, and of course it then puts it into its memory.
そしてもちろん､ それをメモリーに保存する｡
So we're seeing the items that have been surfaced here.
だから､ 私たちはここで浮上した項目を見ている｡
And if I go back over to, uh, the command line, we'll see, of course, that it initialized, it
コマンドラインに戻ると､ もちろん､ 初期化され､
set things up, it got itself ready, uh, and it's now going to be sitting in a loop so that, uh,
セットアップされ､ 準備が整ったことがわかる｡
And after a minute, it will kick off and launch and hopefully you're doing the same thing.
そして1分後､ キックオフして起動する｡
You've opened this up, you're running it, you're going to give this a try.
あなたはこれを開き､ 実行し､ これを試してみようとしている｡
And like me, you will then see it run.
そして､ 私と同じように､ それが走るのを見ることになる｡
And I will go to the next lecture where we will take a look at the outcome.
そして次回の講義では､ その結果について見ていくことにしよう｡
Uh, I will see you there.
そこで会おう｡